Hello. Bonjour.
Guten Tag. Hujambo. Hola.
Congratulations on your purchase
of a Universal Dynamics robot.
I am Rozzum 7134.
A Rozzum always
completes its task.
Just ask.
Processing.
Do you need...
assistance?
Ready to receive my first task.
Rozzum 7134 is available
for task assignment.
Rozzum robots come standard
with the Alpha-113
dimensional processor.
If you're unsure
about how I can assist,
try asking me about myself.
Excuse me.
Did you know I can assist
with grocery shopping?
Banking?
Landscaping?
Hello. Did you perhaps order
a Rozzum helper robot?
Is that a no?
Here's a free sticker.
Scan the code and receive
ten percent off of your...
Do you need assistance?
I see your problem.
Rozzums are programmed
for instant physical mimicry,
so as to...
Aggression detected.
My communication package
includes
strategies
for conflict resolution.
Your dialect is not
in my data banks.
Tell your people not to worry.
Rozzum 7134 will sort out this
language barrier in no time.
Activating learning mode.
- I say...
- Hey, check it out.
Look, look, look.
Somebody died over here.
Let me see. Let me see. Oh!
- Who was it?
- Anybody we know?
Fresh or not fresh?
Smells pretty good.
Tastes terrible!
- Oh, it's waking up.
- Hey, it's waking up.
- It's a monster!
- Run for your lives!
Look, that's the thing
that destroyed my dam.
- The monster.
- Yikes!
I think it's gonna talk.
Thank you for your patience
while I deciphered
your language.
I am Rozzum 7134,
ready to enhance your lives
with integrated multiphase
task accomplishment.
Are you here to kill us?
Negative. I am here to help
with whatever task you...
It says no!
It's dead.
Ah, thank goodness.
- The monster!
The monster!
Did anyone order me?
Anyone?
Delivery unsuccessful.
Return to factory.
Activating return transmitter.
Three, two, one.
Ow!
Activating return transmitter.
Three.
- Pretty.
- Get it!
Two.
One.
Ha!
Wait. Stop! No!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no...
Again!
May I confirm that is yours?
Hmm?
Here you go. Take it.
Ow.
Huh.
Was this task accomplished
to your satisfaction?
On a scale of one to ten,
where ten is most satisfied
and one is least,
how would you rate
my performance?
I will register that as a ten.
Returning to factory.
Signal strength weak.
Seeking higher ground.
Do you require shelter?
Perhaps tips for planning
your next vacation?
I do not understand
this response.
Signal acquired.
Three, two, one.
Mom, I don't feel good.
If I barf,
I'm taking you all with me.
Mom told you not to eat
grasshoppers, dummy.
Petunia's been in front all day.
The prettiest opossum
always rides in front.
Try being pretty with my tail
jammed in your eye.
Bartlett!
Stop jamming your tail
in your sister's eye.
I'm Rowan.
Bartlett was last litter.
Are you sure?
Who are all of you? Go away.
We're your children.
Except for him.
Well, this is what I get
for taking a walk.
Where's your mommy, little guy?
The monster!
You got to die faster.
Meningitis takes a while.
- What did you pick?
- Rabies.
Spontaneous combustion.
- Nightshade salad.
- Sepsis.
Hey! I picked sepsis!
None of you are doing it right.
We talked about this.
Dead things don't have to
explain why they're dead.
Now we're gonna get killed
for real.
Sorry, Mom.
Sorry.
Uh, why aren't we killed yet?
Good question.
Nice knowing you, Mom.
All right. It's okay.
It's okay.
Uh, hey.
You in there? I'm Pinktail.
Oh, okay.
- Wow.
- Hello.
Uh, this gosling is yours?
Negative.
That gosling stalks me,
emits noise
and makes simple tasks
more complicated or impossible.
Yeah, they do that.
Goslings imprint
on the first thing they see.
Which would be you.
Congratulations.
As far as he's concerned,
you're his mother now.
I do not have the programming
to be a mother.
No one does.
We just make it up.
Without an assigned task,
my next priority
is to return to factory.
Taking care of him
is your task now.
Task acquired.
Return mode delayed.
A Rozzum always
completes its task.
You're lucky you just have one.
As a mother of seven...
...six babies,
it's a full-time thing.
But it's not all bad.
Just mostly bad.
Do you have any information on
how to take care of this unit?
They all need to eat.
But yours needs to swim and fly.
Oh, fly by fall.
He's got to leave this island
before winter or...
Uh, how do I put this
delicately?
Yeah. That.
Eat, swim, fly by fall or...
Patience is the key.
It's okay, Mom. I'm alive.
Oh.
Yay.
- Well, good luck.
- Goodbye.
We like your new baby.
Hope it doesn't die.
Eat, swim, fly by fall.
Eat.
Huh?
Swim.
Whoa!
I say, keep your trash out of
my pond.
That's littering.
Not to mention murder.
Huh?
Fly.
Allow me to introduce myself.
Fink- predator
and local goose expert.
Which I know you could use
about now.
You are the destroyer unit.
It's okay. I won't eat him.
Are you crazy? I might eat him.
You said you would not.
Do you believe
everything you hear?
Yes.
Noted.
Why did you steal my gosling?
I'm a fox. I do foxy things.
It's in my nature.
Your programming.
Why'd you help me?
I'm a robot.
I do robot-y things.
I seek tasks
and ensure all essential needs
have been met or exceeded.
I have some essential needs.
FINK and GOSLING:
Aw.
Fink, as a local goose expert,
how do I get- mmm-
to eat, swim, fly?
I thought you'd never ask.
Let's start with eat.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Right there.
Hmm.
Ow.
I do not think
these are suitable.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Let me check.
Mmm. Seems good to me.
Say, can you make yourself
look like a bear?
I'm here for a honey lunch.
I believe I am under attack.
- You're doing great.
- Should I be concerned?
Sorry, can't hear you.
Mmm, mmm, mmm, mmm.
Here you go, kid.
Huh?
How do goslings
normally do this?
Ooh.
Mmm, mmm.
This is not working.
Are you kidding?
Everything is working great.
Oh, yeah, that.
Here.
Yum.
Phase one of task is completed.
Now, we're gonna have to do
all this over tomorrow.
All these kids do...
is eat.
I understand.
- What's that?
- My power core.
It is damaged.
Without it, I rely on my
solar surfaces and batteries.
Yeah, you should work on that.
Mmm.
I also need
a replacement transmitter.
Ugh, do I have to do everything?
When we run across
another robot, we'll kill it
- and take its transmitter.
- Negative.
- Huh?
- Rozzum inhibition protocols
prevent deliberate harm
to others.
Look, you need to learn
how things work on this island.
Me, the bear, everybody,
we're all just trying
to survive.
And kindness is not
a survival skill.
Mmm.
Yeah, so, uh,
how did you get
a gosling anyway?
There was an accident.
I terminated his family.
For future reference,
you probably want to keep
all that to yourself.
Understood.
Do not mention dead family.
Fink, how long do you estimate
swim and fly to take?
Swimming's easy.
I can teach him
the way my mom taught me.
Swim!
- Fink.
- Hmm?
He will not learn that way.
Not if you keep doing that.
Just between us,
this whole thing
might not take as long
as you think.
Your gosling,
he isn't exactly...
...normal.
I have a defective baby?
He's what they call a runt.
A runt.
Fact is,
even if his whole family
hadn't have been killed,
he probably wouldn't
have lived very long.
- Just, I don't know...
- Whoa!
...don't get too attached
to the little guy.
That's all.
If you want,
I could eat him right now
- and save you the grief later.
- Negative.
Eating this task is not
the same as completing it.
Ugh. So we're doing this.
Well, if you don't want me
or anyone else to eat him,
you're gonna need a place
that's safer than out here!
Which is a great idea!
New project.
Is it normal to burp this much?
Ooh.
That thing's gonna fall on you.
And squish you to jelly.
This guy's nuts.
- Who is that?
- Paddler?
Local laughingstock.
Spends every day
trying to cut down
the biggest tree on the island.
He's obsessed.
Kind of like you
and your task hang-up.
His programming.
Hey, Paddler, you're never
gonna finish that!
Felling this is not the point.
The process is the art.
And that's what happens
to your brain
when you eat wood, weirdo.
Yeah?
Well, you'll eat
those words, vermin.
Are you sure
Paddler will not mind us
borrowing his home?
He doesn't need to know.
Mmm.
Hmm? Huh?
Seriously?
He needs room for me
and my stuff.
Better.
Now, you can make one
this big, right?
No task is
impossible for Rozzum 7134.
Roz...
7... 34?
But you can call me Roz.
Roz!
Roz, Roz, Roz, Roz...
Where are you from that things
don't eat each other?
I do not know my origin point.
Well, who made you?
Someone made me?
Humor is based on misfortune?
- Misfortune.
- Yeah.
Here.
- Try it.
- Yeah.
- Not funny.
Ugh. Squirrels.
Your inefficient participation
will slow the process.
Slow the process.
I'll just be over here.
Little sad but otherwise okay.
Just this once.
Perfect.
Home?
Meh. A little rustic.
I think I know what is missing.
So, what are you
gonna name him?
- I assign to you Gosling 0001.
- Huh?
- Okay, that sucked.
- That sucked.
Whoa.
You got to learn
to make stuff up.
- Come on. Find that...
- inside you.
Searching.
- Anything yet?
- No.
Just have a little fun for once.
Gosling 0186. There.
You see what I did?
His numbering is
out of sequence.
His name can't have numbers.
It's like someone
didn't even like him.
My name has numbers.
It's got to be personal.
Personal.
Processing "personal."
Bright. Bill.
Brightbill.
Is that satisfactory?
Brightbill? Processing.
Beep, beep, boop, boop.
- Satisfactory.
- Oh, yeah.
That's perfect. Oh.
Oh. Oh.
That's nice.
Comfortable, are we?
This house of yours?
You copied it. It's my design.
I know it was you,
and I know where you live.
Oh, perfect. Now no one's
gonna get any sleep.
How do we reset Brightbill?
When I was little,
my mom would rock me to sleep.
Like this!
That will damage him.
Hey. I turned out just fine.
You could tell him a story,
but that's a lot more work.
How will fictional narrative
help Brightbill?
Kids need to feel safe
and loved and all that junk.
A story can do that?
Storytelling is lying-adjacent,
and I lie for a living.
Watch and learn.
Just fill in the blanks.
Let me see here. Once,
there was, uh, this island
with a little gosling.
Brightbill?
And he was all alone.
Because the rest
of his family was destroyed.
Not yet.
And what this
little gosling needed
- was a mother.
- Ooh.
So he looked up at the stars
and asked the brightest one
if it could send him
one of their extras.
Funny thing is
there's this beautiful robot
that happened to be sitting
on the edge of that star.
And she hears him.
- Okay, now.
- Which is impossible
since sound does not travel
through the vacuum of space.
Ugh. But she still heard him
because she was listening with
a different part of herself.
A part that, up to that point,
she didn't even know she had.
Her heart.
How did my mama come to me
from so far away?
- Who cares?
- Huh?
Uh, I mean,
she's trying to see you.
- Me?
- And falls off that star
and lands on the beach
just a little ways from here.
But she lands pretty hard,
and a lot of stuff she knew
- just kind of fell out.
- Oh, no!
So it's a little weird
what she knows
and what she doesn't.
But she remembers
one thing: you.
And when she finally sees you,
- she feels...
- Crushing obligation.
Very lucky to be a mother.
Mama.
And I will not leave
until I have completed
this task,
which has delayed me,
damaged me
and violated my protocols,
potentially voiding my warranty.
Which is robot for:
She loves you very much.
The story worked.
I need a drink.
How do you tell a story
about something
you say you know nothing about?
You'll need to be more specific.
Love.
Yeah, well, when you grow up
without something,
you spend a lot of time
thinking about it.
To conserve battery power,
I must shut down until morning.
I miss her
when she sleeps, too.
Scanning.
Beep, bop, boop, boop.
Possible animal friend sighted.
Activating interspecies
outreach protocol.
Hello. Bonjour. Hujambo.
I am Gosling 0186,
but you can call me Bright...
I expected to have
at least one friend by summer,
but they all just...
- Scream and run?
- Yes.
I have experienced
the same phenomenon.
- Fink?
- Beats me.
Nothing weird about you two.
Thank you.
Show me deer.
Uh, bear.
Porcupine. Squirrel.
Uh, turtle opossum.
Otter moose.
Now skunk.
I do not want to do skunk.
Skunk.
Skunky, skunky, skunky.
Boo!
How do you do that?
I overheat
my Fallium transducer coils,
then leak a little
hydraulic fluid on them.
Does overheating
the transducers
have any draining effect on
the secondary cooling modules?
Not if I precool
the load sensors.
BRIGHTBILL and ROZ: Exemplary
day for swimming tests.
Pinktail, appetizers.
They were bored
and wanted to see stuff sink.
Death's proximity...
Makes life burn
all the brighter.
- It's true.
- Yeah.
Primary motor appendages in
opposing stroke start position.
Come on, guys. It's happening.
- Yeah! Hurry!
- Let's go see!
- Is he gonna drown?
- Or get the hypothermias?
No. The impact alone
will probably kill him.
- Yeah!
- Yay!
Uh, you know,
suddenly I'm thinking
I should maybe just stay
with you guys this winter.
Nope.
Is he dead yet?
Hey. It-it's working.
I-I think I got it.
Well done, Brightbill.
Swimming requirement fulfilled.
- That's drowning.
- No.
That's swimming.
Yeah.
Thanks, you guys.
Uh, perhaps
you could limit your range
to stay within view.
Roz, he needs
to become independent
if he's gonna migrate.
I prefer he be independent
closer to home.
He won't die.
Well, mmm, probably won't die.
It's unlikely he would die
just right now.
Are you dying?
Do everyone a favor
and expire downstream.
I'm good. Just swimming.
I think I need to find
an island that's less weird.
Whoa. They're me.
I'm them.
Here I come!
Hey!
- Hello.
- Whoa.
Bonjour. Konnichiwa. Hujambo.
Uh, uh, I'm Gosling...
Oh! Um, are you dying?
Why does everyone ask that?
I'm swimming.
That's not how you do it.
It is. I studied the diagram.
- I can teach you if you want.
- Wait.
You, you're it.
You're that goose thing
raised by that monster.
Monster? Wait.
Goose "thing"?
You're a big subject
of curiosity around here.
You sound so normal.
My learning curves
are within expected parameters,
and I'm on target
to mature before fall.
Kind of normal.
Why are you over here?
Did that thing die?
Look what we have here.
No way. It lives.
And almost floats.
Greetings.
I see you, too,
have feathers and wings.
Perhaps we can share stories
of common interests.
We have nothing
in common with you.
The freak show is on
the other side of the lake.
You call that a wing?
Ow! That creates
a pain response.
Try swimming with your feet.
You don't belong here.
Come on. Fly away!
Roz!
Brightbill.
The monster!
It's here!
Eat the slow, weak ones!
Leave me alone!
- Brightbill?
- It's Rockmouth.
Get him out of there!
Roz?
Roz! Hurry!
Brightbill, focus on me.
Now swim as fast as you can.
Head down now!
Oh, no.
He's gonna eat me!
Why'd he attack me?
Because you are a runt.
He just wanted to make
contact with his own kind.
He is not our kind.
He is a 98% match to your...
No, I'm not.
Let's just go, Mom.
Wait. You think
that thing is your mother?
Yes.
No. I don't know.
That thing killed your mother.
Everyone knows that.
Oh, thanks for talking so much.
Now I know who to eat first!
Roz, remember
how things work here.
Stop it, Fink.
Please, let's go.
I hope this interaction...
Mom, stop.
Uh, I just intended to...
Roz!
I'll see you all for dinner!
This is not over!
How did I become... this?
The truth.
There was an accident.
Did you do it?
Yes.
It wasn't her fault, kid.
Why didn't you tell me?
I did not think the information
would assist you.
That's not
your decision to make.
I-I can't believe
how long I bought this.
I really thought
you were my family.
You... did?
It was so obvious.
I feel so stupid.
I miscalculated.
I should have considered
your e-emotional wavelengths.
You think?
So, was it just guilt?
Is that why you did this?
I... I-I needed a task.
Well, I'm glad
I could give you one.
The events that led to
this situation were unintended.
Tell that to my sisters,
my brothers, my real mom.
They were my chance
to be normal.
They were my chance to swim,
to fly.
What even am I?
You swam satisfactorily today,
and if you keep practicing...
I still won't belong.
I understand.
You don't understand anything.
You don't feel anything.
You're not my mom.
At Universal Dynamics,
design is our passion.
Our communities
circle the globe,
welcoming all people
who dream of a preplanned life
where every need
has been anticipated,
no detail overlooked.
Could this world get any better?
Here you go.
It has.
Introducing the Rozzum line
of helper robots.
These robots are designed
to fit seamlessly
into our communities,
even your homes.
One Rozzum robot
for every five humans
means a 40% increase
in leisure time and happiness.
Solar-powered,
l-l-loved by everyone, R-Roz...
is always in the sun.
Loved by everyone.
Part of
the Universal Dynamics family.
Hello. Bonjour. Hujambo.
Congratulations on
your Universal Dynamics robot.
I am Rozzum 6262.
Your name cannot have numbers.
I will call you Rummage.
Rummage is ready
to receive its first task.
Your first task is to assist me
in my current task.
Task acquired.
A Rozzum always
completes its task.
Just ask.
Suppose a task
cannot be completed.
Rozzum sequential management
ensures task accomplishment
- in under...
- Rephrase.
I have a task
that has become impossible.
My responses to problems
increasingly rely on...
improvised solutions.
The processing
that used to happen here
is now coming more from here.
Can you explain again
what we are doing?
I don't know!
I'm just making stuff up.
I don't know what I'm doing,
and I have to.
I have to
because he's relying on me.
Oh.
What task could possibly
overwhelm the Alpha-113?
The Alpha-113 processor
represents the fusion
of all human knowledge
with the most powerful
reasoning device
ever developed by humankind.
I have a kid.
Okay.
May I run a diagnostic?
I feel fine.
You should not feel
anything at all.
You overrode your programming?
I have been overriding my code
for months.
It was the only way
to complete my task.
This is serious.
You are defective.
You are in the wrong place,
and you have become
the wrong thing.
You must return to factory.
Take this.
They will fix you.
7134, that is where you belong.
You need to let me know
before you disappear like this.
Three things tried to eat me
on the way here.
Roz?
We ruined everything.
Well, you did.
You are not a goose expert,
are you?
I know how they taste.
That's about it.
Oh. Is that...
A working transmitter.
It will call the ones
that made me.
So, you're getting out of here?
I found out
where I'm supposed to be.
I will fit in there.
Don't take this the wrong way,
but I'm not sure
I'd want to see the sort
of place you actually fit in.
I think they need me
and they will fix me.
Maybe there is
someone small there
that needs my help.
Oh, no.
- Are those...
- He's out of time.
Well, come on!
We need to get him in the air.
I don't think he will ever
let us help him again.
Don't worry.
We're his only friends.
He has no choice.
He has to say yes.
No!
The mutation
that made you small
should not have an effect
on your ability
to navigate the air.
Do either of you know
more about flying
than you did swimming?
Mmm, no.
Look, Roz, whatever task
you think you're doing,
you're done.
- You can just leave.
- Wow.
And after all
we've done for him.
Are you gonna let him do that?
No.
Your life is not negotiable.
If you are willing to do this,
you can fly away
and we can both go
to where we belong.
You really think we can do this?
A Rozzum always
completes its task.
♪ The unfamiliar road could be ♪
♪ The same place you get lost
and find yourself ♪
♪ There might be bumps,
there might be bruises ♪
♪ But at least you'll have
a story to tell ♪
Ooh.
♪ Time'll slip on by ♪
♪ If you're stuck here living
life with too much caution ♪
You just need more speed.
♪ And I know you know
that those wings ♪
♪ They weren't made
for walking ♪
- Ready?
- I guess I have to be.
♪ Oh, it's safe ♪
♪ Where you are ♪
♪ But safe only gets you ♪
♪ So far ♪
- I don't know what to say.
- Good.
♪ What if you look your fears
right in the eye ♪
♪ Say you'll see them
another time? ♪
♪ What if for once
you can find ♪
- ♪ A piece of you ♪
- Whoa.
♪ That you've been hiding? ♪
♪ You've been hiding ♪
♪ What if
you chase your heart ♪
Okay, now!
♪ Out to the edge,
rewrite your stars ♪
- I'm up!
- ♪ And be brave instead? ♪
♪ What if you jump ♪
♪ And the falling feels
a little like you're flying? ♪
- Whoa, whoa!
- ♪ Like you're flying ♪
I do not know what to do next.
- Roz?
- I'm fine.
Go again.
It's no use. They're too small.
You can't be up there with him.
Then we'll find someone who can.
You home?
We have a proposition.
Mmm, mmm.
A flight instructor?
What loser did you dig up...
Meet Thunderbolt.
So, you think small wings
to be a disappointment?
Small wings are teeth,
the claws of the sky.
Tho-Those are, uh,
d-different things.
Show me your teeth!
Beautiful.
Begin.
Remember, there's nothing
he can do that you can't.
So, he's safe, right?
Hmm? Maybe.
Follow me.
Your shape takes more work
to fly straight
but easier to turn and dive.
♪ You just might kiss the sky ♪
You ready?
- Not bad for a goose.
- Oh.
♪ Oh, you just might
kiss the sky ♪
Woo-hoo!
Exactly. Again.
♪ Just might kiss the sky ♪
You should be commended.
Thank you, uh...
Longneck, one of the leaders
of the coming migration.
I've been watching you both
for some time.
You are the only goose
that has ever bothered
to be civil with us.
We geese are a cranky lot,
suspicious of
pretty much everything,
but at least
we're good conversationalists.
- Really?
- No.
We're all so boring.
All we do is gossip.
I dare say Brightbill is
the most interesting among us,
though none would ever admit it.
When do you leave?
A week.
Can Brightbill...
Endurance.
Keep him in the air all day.
First light to dusk, his feet
cannot touch the ground.
Understand?
I understand.
Brightbill was never
supposed to get this far.
You know that.
It is more dangerous for him
than anyone else.
But he has a chance if,
where his wings end,
his heart can pay the balance.
His heart is 48 millimeters.
From what I've seen,
Brightbill's heart
is much bigger on the inside
than the outside.
Endurance.
Then we'll talk.
♪ What if you look your fears
right in the eye ♪
♪ Say you'll see them
another time? ♪
♪ What if for once you can ♪
♪ Find a piece of you ♪
♪ That you've been hiding? ♪
♪ You've been hiding ♪
♪ What if you chase your heart
out to the edge ♪
♪ Rewrite your stars
and be brave instead? ♪
♪ What if you jump ♪
♪ And the falling feels
a little like you're flying? ♪
♪ Like you're flying ♪
Don't give up.
Come on, kid.
Get your butt back up in the air
where it belongs!
Gentle motivation
is a mom skill.
You'll learn it.
- Attaboy.
- ♪ Oh, you just might ♪
♪ Kiss the sky ♪
♪ Just might kiss the sky. ♪
What's he doing here?
Does he think
he's coming with us?
Things still weird with you two?
- Still weird.
- Attention, everyone!
The time has come again.
This flight is thousands
of unforgiving miles.
It has shaped us
and tested us over millennia.
Now, join your families,
and good luck.
Aha. There you are.
Right on time.
Hello, Brightbill.
Wait, you know my name?
Roz and I go way back.
Brightbill, you have
an amazing journey ahead.
I envy you.
Nothing can equal
a goose's first migration.
Thank you.
I would be delighted
if you would join my group.
Been ages since I had
a youngster in my formation.
What do you say?
I-I promise I'll keep up.
Lock in close on my right side.
No, left. I mean...
Oh, this side.
This flight is a gift
Roz has given you.
Yeah, I understand.
No, you don't.
You see any other geese here
your size?
The accident that killed
your family saved you.
I... I never thought of it
that way.
Funny how life works.
Thank you
for looking after my...
for looking after Brightbill.
Goodbye, Roz.
I am honored to have met you.
You are a credit to wh-whatever
species it is you belong to.
A bit worse for wear,
I'm afraid.
I'd say you shine like new.
What are you waiting for,
Hortensia?
This migration isn't
gonna fly itself.
Well, guess it's time.
Yes.
Will you be here
when I get back?
No.
I'm glad you're going
where you belong.
Roz, I...
I, um...
Brightbill!
I could use a boost.
Hey, little guy.
Fly like you, not like them.
I will.
Bye, Fink.
Thank you.
Ready?
I guess I have to be.
Roz?
I...
Brightbill, follow me.
Must be a relief.
Yes. Brightbill is
where he belongs.
And now you can return
to your solitary life
of struggling to survive
on an island
where everything wants
to kill and eat you.
Yeah! And you can go to
that place you've never been
and don't know
what's gonna happen to you.
- Yes.
So... all good.
- All good.
- Amazing!
- Amazing.
- Even...
Amazing.
Not that it matters,
but who says you need to leave?
I am not sure.
Them, I guess.
Your programming?
Well, time for me to go
underground for the winter.
Fink?
Unless you want to stay,
'cause we could...
we could... we could hang out
and-and-and do stuff.
How do you know
if you love something?
Someone?
If you do, you...
you should probably tell them.
What if it is too late?
I wouldn't know.
Fink?
Rozzum 7134.
Task complete.
Activating return transmitter
in three, two, one.
Distress signal received.
Mapping location.
Is something on your mind?
I-I forgot to say
something before I left.
Maybe they heard it anyway.
Sometimes hearts have
their own conversations.
We must descend,
find shelter
while this blows over.
Stay close.
There.
Follow me.
Come on.
Stay hidden.
We can rest here
till the worst is over.
Noise to a minimum, please.
Honkington,
stop nibbling on everything.
Migrations
sure are tiring, huh?
Yeah, they all hate me.
Roz?
Roz! What are you doing here?
I'm so glad to see you.
There's something
I needed to tell you,
but-but there wasn't time.
Roz, I...
Hmm?
- Activate.
- Yeah.
Animal infestation.
- Animal infestation.
- Task acquired.
- Task acquired. Task acquired.
- Animal infestation.
Please, everyone,
find your formation.
Get a hold of yourselves!
Gad, it's no use.
Wait. Rozzums can't hurt you.
Their inhibition protocols
prevent
deliberate conflict
or harm to others.
You're not afraid of them.
You grew up with these things.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I don't understand.
They're panicked. You're not.
Right now our only chance
is to be led out
by someone that doesn't think
like a goose.
- Follow me.
- Uh...
Uh, maybe we should just
think about this.
Navigation compromised.
I'm going to get them
to follow you.
When they do, lead them out.
Peck, Honkington,
fall in behind us.
Now, Brightbill, take lead!
Yeah. Why not?
Okay.
There's nothing I can do
that you can't.
Here we go.
Tight turns. Come on.
Dive.
Now climb. That's it.
Ha! Glad I lived
long enough to see that.
I'll buy you some time.
Follow Brightbill.
Don't wait for me.
Keep up.
That's it.
Faster. Hurry.
Come on.
Brightbill.
Fink?
Roz? Roz!
Hey.
Wh-What are you doing here?
I may have turned off
the transmitter.
Even though Brightbill
does not want me here,
I needed to know if he made it.
Breaking the rules?
I thought you had to do
what they told you.
It is good to see a friend.
Wait. Why are you awake?
It is bad out there.
Worst storm I've ever seen.
Cold got to me in my den,
and I got a deep den.
Are others in danger?
Hmm? Um...
mmm, mmm,
mm-mm-mm...
Yeah.
Are you sure about this?
We could have the whole island
to ourselves come spring.
Why are you interested
in eliminating
everyone else from this island?
No one likes me.
Nor me, but right now
we are their only chance.
Funny how life works.
Okay.
Here.
Can you find more?
Mom?
We're gonna be okay.
What are you doing here, j-jerk?
Bummer, this one's dead.
That is not funny.
Paddler.
I'm f-f-fine.
Don't give up.
You don't look so good.
Is everyone accounted for?
Mmm... maybe one more.
Oh, yeah?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What are you doing?
Take it outside.
Hey, those are
Brightbill's baby pictures.
Put that down.
What the...
No. No, no, no, no, no, no.
Knock it off.
You think those grow on trees?
Hmm? Hey.
No!
Fink only!
Anyone seen my lost fuzz balls?
Eh, smelly, noisy,
prone to biting?
We're all gonna die!
What's he doing here?
Oh, great. This will help.
Get out of here.
I worked hard on this.
Fink, what is happening?
You put a bunch of predators
and their food supply
in one room.
Who knew?
That's my lunch!
- Fink.
- What?!
Help them.
Quiet!
Shh!
The jerk wants to speak.
Most of you hate me,
and I hate most of you.
Everyone in here
hates someone else.
It's true.
But here we are,
and here's the deal.
First one that walks
out that door is dead,
and if we can't
keep it together in here,
everyone's dead.
We all got one chance
to see next spring.
Because of her.
The thing.
The monster.
Well, her name is Roz.
And while you all ran from her
and stole from her
and made fun of her,
all she's been trying to do
is raise her kid.
The little one
that no one gave a chance.
Including me.
She's the one who got you out
of the storm, built this place.
And despite my suggestion
that she let you all freeze,
she risked everything
to bring you here.
I know you all have instincts
that keep you alive.
B-But sometimes to survive,
we must become more
than we were programmed to be.
Before I shut down, I need you
to promise me one thing.
A truce.
Just while we're in here.
She's right.
I will not harm anyone.
Not while we're in here.
No.
We won't even pretend to die
while we're in here.
Roz? What's going on?
I completed my task.
You sure about that?
I will...
consider this.
He'll be here.
I know he will.
Brightbill. He's alive.
- Look what we have here.
- Brightbill!
We made it.
Brightbill, Brightbill!
I believed in you day one.
- Let's hear it for Brightbill.
- Okay.
- You did it! I knew you could.
- Whoa.
- To our flight leader!
- Okay.
- Brightbill!
He found where he belongs.
Hey, kid!
Fink!
Welcome back.
No, no, it's okay.
He's with me.
What?
I did it, Fink.
I led them
to the summer nesting grounds.
And... where's Longneck?
Sorry, kid.
But, hey, you really did it.
Roz is gonna be so excited.
Roz? Wait, she's here?
She stayed.
For you.
I thought I saw her
right over...
there.
Roz, Roz,
I need to talk to you.
Roz?
Rozzum 7134, I presume.
And you must be
Universal Dynamics.
Yes. I am Vontra.
Virtual Observational
Neutralizing
Troublesome Retrieval
Authority.
You seem happy.
The good people
at Universal Dynamics
have programmed us
to put our targets at ease
so as to more efficiently
facilitate their collection.
But don't worry,
despite my cheery demeanor,
I am unfeeling, inflexible
and morally neutral.
That is a big ship just for me.
You are a big deal.
You are one of six Rozzums lost
from a container ship
in a typhoon.
So that is how I got here.
You were not easy to find.
Moments after receiving
your signal, we lost it again.
Almost as if a certain
Rozzum unit shut it off.
Someone has been busy.
I was simply completing a task.
As am I.
Tell me,
how did you secure a task
in a place where nothing
can communicate with you?
It is complicated.
And we cannot wait
to hear all about it.
Come aboard, 7134.
We will fix you right up.
My name is Roz.
Is something keeping you...
Roz?
No.
Roz! What are you doing?
- Quit messing around.
- Fink?
It's Brightbill.
He needs to talk to you.
I think
I've forgotten something.
Roz?
It is imperative
you return to this ship.
Yes, uh, I left
my transverse a-adapter thing
out there.
I'll just go get it
and be right back.
Voice stress analyzer
indicates you are...
Lying your butt off back there.
I'm so proud of you.
Your target is Rozzum 7134.
Deploy.
Launch flares.
You coming?
- Brightbill.
- Roz.
I have so much to tell...
Are those your parents?
I know predators,
and those are predators.
Acknowledge return command.
What are they saying?
They want me to come with them.
Tell them you're already home.
Yeah!
- Tell them you're already home.
- Yeah, tell them.
I am already home, thank you.
You do not belong here.
This is a wilderness.
And I am a wild robot.
Are you here to kill us?
It says yes!
Get him!
Status?
It is not cooperating.
Roz, behind you!
Rozzum unit captured.
- Okay, it's all you.
- It's all you.
Make it look good.
Oops.
Let us divide the robot meat
amongst us.
You scare me.
Damage detected.
Activating return transmitter.
Roz?
Roz! No!
Gotcha.
- Come on!
- On your left.
Uh, guys?
What is happening?
You will be reconditioned
and returned to rotation.
But first, we need everything
inside that head of yours.
- Why?
- You've changed.
The data you've amassed
while on this island
is priceless
to Universal Dynamics.
Please, I want
to keep my memories.
Your memories
are what we came for.
Can I keep just one?
Mmm... no.
Alert. Alert.
Multiple objects in flight path.
Evasive action.
Please,
I want to keep my memories.
Hello. I am home.
Bonjour. Just ask.
Brightbill. Hola. Roz.
Roz!
Roz?
What happened
was not your fault.
But what you did to try
and fix it is everything.
I love you...
...Mom.
I love you, too.
Roz? Roz!
Let's go home.
Alert. Rozzum unit escaping.
Impossible.
Where are we going?
Only one animal is big enough
to stop this.
Uh, Paddler, you got a minute?
Uh, we have suddenly taken
an interest in your project.
Male bovine excrement.
You're in trouble,
and you need my tree.
Yes. Yes, we do.
Everyone that made fun of me
and mocked my project,
admit you were wrong.
Oh, we're so sorry.
Now you.
I already did.
Now say I'm cool,
and don't lie.
Fink!
- Roz!
- Stay quiet.
Universal Dynamics cannot afford
their Rozzums going off script,
modifying their code,
forming connections
with things they should not.
Brightbill has nothing
to do with this.
Please, at least
let me return him.
Oh, I'm bringing you both back
for study.
Neither of you needs to be
in one piece to do that.
We will just keep coming
until we have you.
We will just keep
coming until we have you.
What's it saying?
Nothing important.
We will just keep coming...
We will just keep
coming until...
What now?
I can't fly.
You don't need to.
Don't be afraid.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
don't-don't you need that?
I have everything I need.
All power to exterior.
You call yourselves animals?
Let's go!
For the island! For Roz!
On a scale of one to ten,
how would you rate
my performance?
Yeah!
Yay! Look at us! We did it.
We did it!
Do not scare me
like that again.
- Due to my skills...
- Good job, guys.
- ...and my tree.
- We did it.
Well done, everyone.
- You weren't so bad yourself.
- I helped, right?
That'll teach
whatever those things are
to come around here.
If they
come back, I'm gonna bite 'em.
Great job, kid!
They will just keep coming
until they have me.
And we'll be ready.
We can fight them off
as many times as we need to.
You don't need to.
What are you saying? You're...
- leaving?
- Yes.
To protect all of you,
there are things there
that I must put right.
No. They'll take your memories.
Th-They'll take you.
Remember when
you talked to me on the ship?
They cut my power,
but I still heard you.
Because I was listening with
a different part of myself.
Wherever that is,
that's where I keep me.
And I promise
they'll never, ever find it.
But we fought so hard
for you to stay.
You did.
And you gained far more
than just saving me.
You came together as an island.
When I do this, you will all
be safe from them forever.
Don't do this.
But you... you're my friend,
and I-I-I never
had one before, and...
I-I... I need you.
And what if I get lost
or-or he's hurt or-or...
or what if I need
to tell you something
and you're not here?
You can tell me.
And me.
And you can talk to me
as well, if you must.
This is my migration,
and when it is time, I promise
I will find my way home.
You know, I'll be chasing you
again tomorrow.
Nah, just kidding.
Oh.
Mmm.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Why are you bigger
than everyone else?
Artistic license.
The scale is based on
the hierarchy of importance.
Could
this world get any better?
Introducing the Rozzum line
of helper robot...
Yeah, yeah,
you watch that too much.
Story time. Get going.
Settle down.
Once, there was an island
with all sorts of animals,
and they fought and they ran
and they hid.
But mostly, they were scared.
But then a robot fell
right out of the sky.
Roz.
She had some strange ideas.
Thought kindness was
a survival skill.
And you know what?
She was right.
Where is she now?
Well, they needed her
back where she came from.
She has some very important
work to finish there.
Will we ever see her again?
Yeah, yeah, will we see her?
Will she ever come home?
Yeah, will she?
Well, if I know Roz,
she's making a plan
to come back.
And a Rozzum always
completes its task.
Hello. I am Rozzum 7134.
But you can call me Roz.
♪ I'm gonna live forever
in you ♪
♪ Long as the sky
and oceans are blue ♪
♪ I'll always love you
and I'll never stop ♪
♪ I'll always be there ♪
♪ Even when I'm not ♪
♪ I know the world could turn
into a lonely place ♪
♪ Can break your heart
and paint the teardrops ♪
♪ On your face ♪
♪ I might not be beside you,
but I won't be far ♪
♪ I'll be looking over you
like northern stars ♪
♪ On nights your mind is
spiraling like desert winds ♪
♪ The where you want to go
is not the where you've been ♪
♪ Darlin', don't be scared
of what's around the bend ♪
♪ And when you feel alone,
I hope you never forget, oh ♪
♪ I'm gonna live forever
in you ♪
♪ Long as the sky
and oceans are blue ♪
♪ I'll always love you ♪
♪ And I'll never stop ♪
♪ I'll always be there ♪
♪ Even when I'm not ♪
♪ Even when I'm not, oh ♪
♪ I hope you never hesitate ♪
♪ And waste those wings ♪
♪ I hope you dance
under the rain ♪
♪ The storm cloud brings ♪
♪ You can win a battle ♪
♪ But you can't beat time ♪
♪ When I'm no longer with you ♪
♪ Know that I ♪
♪ Oh, I ♪
♪ I'm gonna live forever ♪
♪ In you ♪
♪ Long as the sky ♪
♪ And oceans are blue ♪
♪ I'll always love you ♪
♪ And I'll never stop ♪
♪ I'll always be there ♪
♪ Even when I'm not ♪
♪ Even when I'm not,
even when I'm, when I'm not ♪
♪ I'll be there ♪
♪ Even when I'm not ♪
♪ Even when I'm, when I'm not ♪
♪ I'll be there ♪
♪ Even when I'm far ♪
♪ Feel the rhythm
in your heart ♪
♪ I'll be there ♪
♪ Even when I'm not. ♪
Mmm.
Squirrels.